https://www.woodcraftschool.co.uk/about/woodcraft-school-policies

Email UsFacebookiconsLinkedIniconsTwitter
HomeAboutAbout UsTerms & ConditionsPoliciesCoursesBushcraft & Natural History CoursesCourse CalendarBooksVideosArticlesTalksContact Us
Search for:
Home About Woodcraft School Policies
New course24-28 March 2020Combined tracker workshop and evaluationA 3 day Track and sign workshop followed by a 2 day evaluationMore InfoDates for 2020Tracker Evaluations2020 dates available for track and sign and trailingMore InfoPlaces available29 June-3 July 2020Plant identification for wild foods and MedicineAn excellent exploration into the world of plants and treesMore Info
Woodcraft School PoliciesPrivacy PolicyWoodcraft School Ltd (“We”) commit ourselves to protecting and respecting your privacy when visiting our website.This privacy policy sets out how we will process and use any personal data that you provide to us, or that we may collect as a result of visiting www.woodcraftschool.co.uk. Please read the following information to understand our practices with regards to your personal data and how we will treat it.For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, the identity of our data controller shall be available upon enquiry by email.GeneralThroughout this statement, Woodcraft School and references to ‘this site’ or ‘this website’ are to be read as meaning the same entity.Woodcraft School is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Under no circumstances, except where we are legally bound by a recognised law enforcement agency, criminal court or other recognised legal institution, divulge to any third party, any personal details concerning any user of this site. This may include electronic mail (e.mail) address, postal address, name(s), or other personal details submitted to us. We do not sell, rent or trade e.mail details (or any other personal details) with any third party without your consent.Where applicable our site’s contact form requires users to give us contact information (like their name and email address). The visitor’s contact information is only used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section on the relevant page.Woodcraft School may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 01/03/2012What we collectWe may collect the following information:Name and job titleContact information including email addressDemographic information such as postcode, preferences and interestsAny information that you provide by filling in forms on our site. This includes provided information at the time of registering to use our site, posting material, requesting further services or subscribing to any service offered by us on the site. We might also request further information and if you should report a problem with our site.We may keep a record of any correspondence if you should contact us.Details of the resources you access and of your visits to our site.Details of transactions you may carry out through our site and of the completion of your orders.What we do with the information we gatherWe require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:Internal record keepingTo register you with the Website and to administer the Website servicesWe may use the information to improve our products and servicesWe may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.To ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective and appropriate manner for you and for your computer.To notify you about changes to our services.Disclosure of Your InformationWe may disclose your personal information to third parties:To the prospective buyer of our business or assets in the event that we sell.If we are under a duty to comply with any legal obligation to disclose or share your personal data. To protect the rights, property and safety of our customers or others, or to enforce our terms of use for the site. For the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction this may include exchanging information with other companies and organisations.To companies who process information and provide support services on Woodcraft School behalf (please contact us if you want to know who they are)Who are our employees and agents so that they can administer your contract and involvement with Woodcraft School and any user discussion groups on the Website;To whom Woodcraft School transfers our rights or duties under any agreements with you.SecurityWoodcraft School ensures that wherever possible, security measures are in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control (e.g. we actively encourage the use of secure online trading facilities). Please ensure that you are satisfied with the visited site’s own security measures before purchasing goods and/or services.How we use cookiesA cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences and this information is used:.to estimate a web page’s audience size and usage pattern;to store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise the Website according to your individual intereststo speed up your searchesto recognise you when you return to the Website.Woodcraft School website uses Google Analytics – this is a tool that uses a cookie to record anonymous website traffic data. Woodcraft School uses Google Analytics to improve the functioning of our website by analysing visitors’ website behaviour. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system If you would prefer not to show your visit please turn off your cookies in your browser. You should be aware however that with cookies turned off some aspects of our website may not function at their full potentialA cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. Cookies do not contain confidential data such as your name, credit card details etc.Our system will issue cookies when you log onto the Website.This information includes your IP address where available, operating system and browser type, for system administration. Any such system will not create individual profiles for visitors nor will we create a database of individual profiles for each visitor.Links to other websitesOur website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.Controlling your personal informationYou may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:PLEASE NOTE IF PAYING THROUGH THE WEBSITE WE WILL NOT SEE YOUR CARD DETAILS AS THIS IS SECURED VIA PAYPAL. IF YOU DECIDED TO PAY OVER THE PHONE YOUR CARD DETAILS WILL BE KEPT IN A SAFE AND SECURE MANNER AND WILL BE DISPOSED OF FOLLOWING COMPLETION OF YOUR COURSE.We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting.If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.Fraud ProtectionTo protect you, ourselves and others from deception fraud and theft, we may pass on information that we obtain from you or our identity checks to certain organisations (including law enforcement services).Where we store your personal dataThe data Woodcraft School collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, reputable destinations outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by persons operating outside the EEA who work for us. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and afforded the same level of protection as that required of Woodcraft School under UK data protection legislation.All information you provide is stored on our or our vetted and contracted agents’ secure servers.Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although Woodcraft School will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website. Therefore, you accept that any transmission is at your own risk and you will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless this is due to our negligence or wilful default. Once we have received your information, Woodcraft Schoolwill use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. We will retain your information for a reasonable period or as long as the law requires.FlashThe Website may use Flash technology to enhance your experience. If so, and if your computer does not currently have Flash, the Websites are designed to automatically display non-Flash graphic alternatives. Flash is supported by Microsoft Internet Explorer and Mozilla Firefox browsers. Flash has to be downloaded, but only once, and it is free.Changes to our Privacy PolicyWe shall be entitled to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time by posting revisions on this page of the Website.ContentThe website and its content are the property of Woodcraft School. Any photographs, graphics, designs and text cannot be copied or used without prior written consent. You may, however, be able to copy electronically or print portions of the site for personal use.If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy statement then please send your queries to info@woodcraftschool.co.uke-mail protected Operational PoliciesActivities are covered by Education Act 2006 and H&S @ Wk Act 1974 and Regulations 1999.All staff have had a satisfactory Enhanced CRB checkHealth & safetyThe health and safety of the group is safeguarded through assessing risk, managing risk, educating the group, training staff and establishing an emergency plan.Risk assessments are carried out for the site, the group and the specific activities. These assessments are acted on to eliminate the risk or reduce it to an appropriate level. The Lead Instructor will check the site before the group arrives to ensure that everything is in order. On-going risk assessment is carried out by the group to identify and act on any changes in situation. The action points from the risk assessments are detailed in the Risk Management Plan.Woodcraft School Instructors are trained in First Aid and will carry emergency equipment including a First Aid Kit. The Emergency Plan is known by all members of the group including the participants and additional daily safety points are explained in morning briefing or at the start of an activity.Woodcraft School keeps an Accident Book to record details of injuries that must be reported under the Reporting of Injuries, Diseases and Dangerous Occurences Regulations 1995. Any incidents are used to inform future planning and improve the Risk Management Plan.InsuranceOur insurance is provided by acknowledged specialists Jardine Lloyd Thompson Leisure under their “Adventure Activity Insurance Scheme” to include Public and Products Liability for £5,000,000 with Errors and Omissions for £100,000.Photographs and VideosPhotographs and videos taken during the course of activities will be treated with the utmost respect. Please advise us prior to any course if you do not want your image to appear on any form of Woodcraft School advertising.All media given to Woodcraft School by a group is assumed to have permission for inclusion in promotional material such as leaflets, fliers and websites unless we are informed otherwise.All media will be vetted to ensure that images are appropriate and considerate of the subject. Images will never be labelled with names or other personal details.If you have any concerns about images displayed in Woodcraft School material please contact us as soon as possible and we will aim to remedy the situation as soon as possible.Concerns or complaintsIn the event of concerns or complaints please speak to the Lead Instructor during the course to enable us to rectify any issues. Where resolution is not found please email or write to Woodcraft School, PO Box 64, Midhurst, West Sussex GU29 9WL who will take necessary action.Environmental ImpactWoodcraft School promotes the sustainable use of woodlands for leisure and education. All sites are assessed to establish likely Environmental Impact and measures are outlined to protect the sites.It is the aim of Woodcraft School to teach people about their environmental impact, aspects of sustainable management and the history of woodland management in the UK. Back To Top
Courses Calendar
Join NewsletterOrganisation MemberLatest ArticlesCyberTracker the systemThoughts On Debris SheltersHow to light a campfireTracking BasicsLatest VideosFrog predationMammal TrackingMaking Bark BasketsTraditional Bows Bushcraft & Natural History CoursesHomeAboutAbout UsTerms & ConditionsPoliciesCoursesBushcraft & Natural History CoursesCourse CalendarBooksVideosArticlesTalksContact UsHomeAboutAbout UsTerms & ConditionsPoliciesCoursesBushcraft & Natural History CoursesCourse CalendarBooksVideosArticlesTalksContact Us HomeAboutAbout UsTerms & ConditionsPoliciesCoursesBushcraft & Natural History CoursesCourse CalendarBooksVideosArticlesTalksContact Us HomeAboutAbout UsTerms & ConditionsPoliciesCoursesBushcraft & Natural History CoursesCourse CalendarBooksVideosArticlesTalksContact Us© 2020 Woodcraft School Ltd. All Rights Reserved Website by Bristles & Keys
